Iskren Ivanov

Software Engineer

A communicative and enthusiastic developer who likes to find creative solutions to complicated problems of any scope. Passioned about data and UI/UX. With more than 5 years of commercial experience as a Front End & Full Stack Developer from mature large corporate projects to Greenfield and POC projects.



	\checkmark	iskren930	@gmail.com
--	--------------	-----------	------------

Lambertus Zijlplein 73, 1067JR, Amsterdam, Netherlands

in linkedin.com/in/iskrenivanov

github.com/lsklvanov

-		
	∔ 31	6 42494693
۰	131	0 72777075

iskren.dev

twitter.com/dev_iskren

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Front End Engineer - FreelanceBol.com

11/2021 - Present Utrecht

Largest e-commerce platform in the Benelux region.

Achievements/Tasks

- Implementing large-scale web applications with React in the most visited webshop in Benelux.
- Advocate of high code quality and engineering best practices.
- Came up with new architectural ideas and technical solutions.
- Developed, configured, supported and optimised multiple React applications within bol.com webshop.
- Refactored older React implementations and introduced new libraries to the codebase - React Query, react-hoot-form etc.
- Made contributions on back end code both on monolith codebase and smaller micro services.
- Worked in an Agile environment, shipped multiple features to production after every sprint, conducted code review, made small demos to PO and other stakeholders.
- Proposed different state management tooling and helper libraries to code owners within bol.com
- Demystified tech debt tickets and helped to scope and prioratise the implementation.
- Tech Stack- | React, TypeScript, Storybook, RTL, Next.js, Styled Components.
 Back End: Java, Spring Boot, Kotlin

Contact: Carlien Nijland - cnijland@bol.com

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages

JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS (SCSS/Less), Node.js, SQL, Java

Technologies & Libraries

React, Context API, Storybook.js Redux, RESTfull API, GraphQL, Next.js, Styled Components, Material UI, Bootstrap, GreenSock.js, Pixi.js, React Native, jQuery

Programming paradigms

Object Oriented Programming and Functional Programming

Testing

Unit Testing, Integration Tesing, E2E Testing

Methodologies

Agile, Scrum, Kanban, DevOps & CI/CD

Tools

Git, JIRA, Confluence, Bitbucket, GitHub, Visual Studio Code, Web Storm, IntelliJ IDEA, Postman, DevTools, Bash, Docker, AWS, Firebase

SOFT SKILLS



WORK EXPERIENCE

Front End Engineer

Circularise

03/2021 - 11/2021 Netherlands

Circularise is a startup that brings transparency to global supply chains.

Achievements/Tasks

- Developed a dashboard to easily create, maintain and transact digital assets for supply chain traceability system.
- Built a POC that integrated web3.js to interact with Ethereum blockchain.
- Developed multiple react application from the ground up and reused components.
- Integrated multiple scalable npm packages e.g. Okta, React Query, Formik.
- Analyzed health, maintainability and scalability of external npm packages e.g. licensing, contributors and community, to understand if it is a good fit for our project.
- Wrote technical documentation about features, components, and third-party libraries integrated into the system.
- Led ongoing product discussions with Circularise stakeholders and team members to clarify both businesses, technical and UI/UX requirements in order to improve UI flows and implement new features.
- Worked in an Agile environment, shipped multiple features after every sprint, and did a small demo to Circularise members and stakeholders.
- Consumed RESTfull APIs and collaborated with Back End Engineers on the development and improvements of API endpoints.
- Tech Stack: |React, TypeScript, Next.js, Styled Components, React Query|

Contact: Kilian Marjew - kilian@circularise.com

Front End Engeneer - Freelance Greener Power Solutions

12/2020 - 02/2021 Amsterdam

Startup focused on delivering green energy from festivals to households.

Achievements/Tasks

- For this assignment I built a small MVP for Energy management system.
- Developed a UI from the ground up with React, TypeScript and Material UI.
- Integrated open-source libraries eg. Auth0, Formik, Graphana, GSAP and researched a few more to fit the use case of the EMS.
- Proposed the development of custom design system.
- Proposed, discussed and analysed UI solutions with Software Architect and CTO.
- Researched and proposed the implementation of different libraries and frameworks for the codebase of a green field project.

Contact: Jim van Oosten - jim@greener.nl

PERSONAL PROJECTS

RSVP App

 React Application for receiving responses from people interested in a particular event: https://github.com/lsklvanov/RSVPapp

Score Board App

 Simple scoreboard application build with React: https://github.com/lsklvanov/ReactScoreBoardApp

CERTIFICATES

MTA: Software Development Fundamentals (06/2016 - 08/2016)

LANGUAGES

Enalish

Full Professional Proficiency

Bulgarian

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Dutch

Elementary Proficiency

INTERESTS

Chess | Snowboarding

Cycling

Travel

Weightlifting

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Engineer

Accenture

01/2019 - 05/2020

Sofia, Bulgaria

Fortune 500 company.
Achievements/Tasks

- Worked on multiple e-commerce projects for major corporate clients which all were recognized for meeting client expectations.
- Contributed to a large codebase with reliable and scalable code.
- Heavily contributed to e-commerce rebuild, migrating from jQuery to React and TypeScipt.
- Contributed to numerous Back end services for a large e-commerce distributed application.
- Worked in an Agile environment with teams located in multiple countries within EU, following Scrum methodology.
- Delivered multiple features after every sprint and did demo to project stakeholders after each sprint.
- Worked within Agile team, shipped multiple features at the end of every spring.
 Did small demos after each sprint to customers and stakeholders.
- Proficiently troubleshoot simple and complex technical issues of any scope for differently assigned projects, optimized speed and stability over a variety of web aplications.
- Tech Stack: | JavaScript, TypeScript, React, HTML/SCSS, Node.js, Express, Python, FastAPI, MongoDB, NoSQL |

Front End Engineer - Games SkywindGroup Ltd.

04/2018 - 12/2018

Sofia, Bulgaria

Global entertainment technology solution provider.

Achievements/Tasks

- Developed and optimized Interactive Slot Casino Games and SDK.
- Worked closely with designers, animators and project managers to create new game features.
- Consumed RESTful APIs and discussed API improvements with Back End engineer and mathematician.
- Worked in an Agile-driven environment to effectively maintain project timelines and utilize available resources.
- Fixed bugs in all stages of the development while taking ownership for features before and after deployment.
- Contributed to the development of a modular MVC SDK.
- Tech Stack: |TypeScript, Pixi.js, GSAP, Webpack, Node.js, Gulp, Jest|

Front End Developer Dantek Ltd.

02/2017 - 02/2018

Sofia, Bulgaria

Creative marketing agency.

Achievements/Tasks

- Developed dynamic web pages using HTML5 ,SCSS, JavaScipt ,jQuery and Bootstrap to meet usability and performance requirements.
- Introduces React to the workflow and helped other developers to understand it and create reusable UI components.
- Designed and Developed landing pages and email templates by utilizing the latest UX standards and trends.
- Led collaboration efforts between marketing and design teams to develop innovative landing pages and emails.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's of Automation and Information Engineering Technical University of Gabrovo

09/2012 - 06/2016

85% Overall Award Avarage

Thesis

 Web Application for Holiday Planning https://github.com/IskIvanov/Holida y_planner